[
    {
        "genre": "過去形",
        "list": [
            {
                "question": "beの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "was",
                    "were",
                    "been",
                    "being"
                ],
                "answer": "was"
            },
            {
                "question": "becomeの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "became",
                    "becomed",
                    "becoming",
                    "become"
                ],
                "answer": "became"
            },
            {
                "question": "beginの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "began",
                    "beginned",
                    "beginning",
                    "begin"
                ],
                "answer": "began"
            },
            {
                "question": "breakの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "broke",
                    "breaked",
                    "breaking",
                    "break"
                ],
                "answer": "broke"
            },
            {
                "question": "catchの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "caught",
                    "catched",
                    "catching",
                    "catch"
                ],
                "answer": "caught"
            },
            {
                "question": "chooseの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "chose",
                    "choosed",
                    "choosing",
                    "choose"
                ],
                "answer": "chose"
            },
            {
                "question": "comeの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "came",
                    "comed",
                    "coming",
                    "come"
                ],
                "answer": "came"
            },
            {
                "question": "doの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "did",
                    "doed",
                    "done",
                    "doing"
                ],
                "answer": "did"
            },
            {
                "question": "drinkの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "drank",
                    "drinked",
                    "drinking",
                    "drink"
                ],
                "answer": "drank"
            },
            {
                "question": "driveの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "drove",
                    "drived",
                    "driving",
                    "drive"
                ],
                "answer": "drove"
            },
            {
                "question": "eatの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "ate",
                    "eated",
                    "eating",
                    "eat"
                ],
                "answer": "ate"
            },
            {
                "question": "findの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "found",
                    "finded",
                    "finding",
                    "find"
                ],
                "answer": "found"
            },
            {
                "question": "flyの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "flew",
                    "flied",
                    "flying",
                    "fly"
                ],
                "answer": "flew"
            },
            {
                "question": "getの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "got",
                    "getted",
                    "getting",
                    "get"
                ],
                "answer": "got"
            },
            {
                "question": "giveの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "gave",
                    "gived",
                    "giving",
                    "give"
                ],
                "answer": "gave"
            },
            {
                "question": "goの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "went",
                    "goed",
                    "going",
                    "go"
                ],
                "answer": "went"
            },
            {
                "question": "haveの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "had",
                    "haved",
                    "having",
                    "have"
                ],
                "answer": "had"
            },
            {
                "question": "knowの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "knew",
                    "knowed",
                    "knowing",
                    "know"
                ],
                "answer": "knew"
            },
            {
                "question": "loseの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "lost",
                    "losed",
                    "losing",
                    "lose"
                ],
                "answer": "lost"
            },
            {
                "question": "makeの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "made",
                    "maked",
                    "making",
                    "make"
                ],
                "answer": "made"
            },
            {
                "question": "meetの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "met",
                    "meeted",
                    "meeting",
                    "meet"
                ],
                "answer": "met"
            },
            {
                "question": "readの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "read",
                    "readed",
                    "reading",
                    "reads"
                ],
                "answer": "read"
            },
            {
                "question": "runの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "ran",
                    "runned",
                    "running",
                    "run"
                ],
                "answer": "ran"
            },
            {
                "question": "sayの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "said",
                    "sayed",
                    "saying",
                    "say"
                ],
                "answer": "said"
            },
            {
                "question": "seeの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "saw",
                    "seed",
                    "seen",
                    "seeing"
                ],
                "answer": "saw"
            },
            {
                "question": "singの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "sang",
                    "singed",
                    "singing",
                    "sing"
                ],
                "answer": "sang"
            },
            {
                "question": "speakの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "spoke",
                    "spoked",
                    "speaking",
                    "speak"
                ],
                "answer": "spoke"
            },
            {
                "question": "takeの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "took",
                    "taken",
                    "taking",
                    "take"
                ],
                "answer": "took"
            },
            {
                "question": "tellの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "told",
                    "telled",
                    "telling",
                    "tell"
                ],
                "answer": "told"
            },
            {
                "question": "thinkの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "thought",
                    "thinked",
                    "thinking",
                    "think"
                ],
                "answer": "thought"
            },
            {
                "question": "writeの過去形は？",
                "options": [
                    "wrote",
                    "writed",
                    "writing",
                    "write"
                ],
                "answer": "wrote"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "genre": "未来形",
        "list": [
            {
                "question": "willは何詞？",
                "options": [
                    "副詞",
                    "名詞",
                    "動詞",
                    "形容詞"
                ],
                "answer": "副詞"
            },
            {
                "question": "willの否定形は？",
                "options": [
                    "wiln't",
                    "willn't",
                    "won't",
                    "willnot"
                ],
                "answer": "won't"
            },
            {
                "question": "be going toの意味は？",
                "options": [
                    "〜する予定",
                    "〜している",
                    "〜するかも",
                    "〜しなければならない"
                ],
                "answer": "〜する予定"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "genre": "1-Lesson11 全書き",
        "answerType": "input",
        "list": [
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n私の街には動物園があります。",
                "options": [
                    "There is a zoo in my town.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There is a zoo in my town."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n動物園には2匹の白いトラがいます。",
                "options": [
                    "There are two white tigers in the zoo.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There are two white tigers in the zoo."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n3年前、動物園の近くにはショッピングモールがありました。",
                "options": [
                    "There was a shopping mall near the zoo three years ago.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There was a shopping mall near the zoo three years ago."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n街にはたくさんの観光客がいました。",
                "options": [
                    "There were a lot of tourists in the town.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There were a lot of tourists in the town."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nこの道には一つも信号機がありません。",
                "options": [
                    "There aren't any traffic lights on this road.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There aren't any traffic lights on this road."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n私たちの学校には図書館（図書室）がありません。",
                "options": [
                    "There is no library in our school.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There is no library in our school."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n10年前、この島には信号機がありませんでした。",
                "options": [
                    "There were no traffic lights on this island ten years ago.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There were no traffic lights on this island ten years ago."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nあなたの家の近くにスーパーマーケットはありますか？",
                "options": [
                    "Is there a supermarket near your house?",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "Is there a supermarket near your house?"
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nはい、あります。（単数）",
                "options": [
                    "Yes, there is.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "Yes, there is."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nいいえ、ありません。（単数）",
                "options": [
                    "No, there isn't.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "No, there isn't."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nこの島にはいくつかコーヒーショップはありますか？",
                "options": [
                    "Are there any coffee shops on this island?",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "Are there any coffee shops on this island?"
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nはい、あります。（複数）",
                "options": [
                    "Yes, there are.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "Yes, there are."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nいいえ、ありません。（複数）",
                "options": [
                    "No, there aren't.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "No, there aren't."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n日本にはたくさんのきれいな場所があります。",
                "options": [
                    "There are a lot of beautiful places in Japan.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There are a lot of beautiful places in Japan."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n沖縄ではたくさん雨が降りますか？",
                "options": [
                    "Is there a lot of rain in Okinawa?",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "Is there a lot of rain in Okinawa?"
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n沖縄では少し雪が降ります。",
                "options": [
                    "There is little snow in Okinawa.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There is little snow in Okinawa."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n北海道ではたくさん雪が降りますか？",
                "options": [
                    "Is there much snow in Hokkaido?",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "Is there much snow in Hokkaido?"
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n私たちはコーヒーを3カップとオレンジジュースを5杯欲しいです。",
                "options": [
                    "We want three cups of coddee and five glasses of orange juice.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "We want three cups of coddee and five glasses of orange juice."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nペンと紙が一枚必要です。",
                "options": [
                    "I need a pen and a sheet of paper.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "I need a pen and a sheet of paper."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nこのホテルには部屋がいくつありますか？",
                "options": [
                    "How many rooms are there in this hotel?",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "How many rooms are there in this hotel?"
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n20あります。",
                "options": [
                    "There are twenty.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There are twenty."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nエントランスに生徒は何人いましたか？",
                "options": [
                    "How many students were there at the entrance?",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "How many students were there at the entrance?"
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\n8いました。",
                "options": [
                    "There were eight.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "There were eight."
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nポットにはどれくらい砂糖が入っていますか？",
                "options": [
                    "How much suger is there in the pot?",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "How much suger is there in the pot?"
            },
            {
                "question": "次の文を英訳しなさい。\nほんの少しです。",
                "options": [
                    "Only a little.",
                    "",
                    "",
                    ""
                ],
                "answer": "Only a little."
            }
        ]
    }
]